Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
在前面的故事里…
There is one who Prime seems to respect.
有一名霸天虎受到擎天柱的尊敬
Dreadwing, there is another path.
骇翼 你有另一个选择
Is there a point to your bluster, Prime?
你这样喋喋不休有意义吗 擎天柱？
The download of the Iacon database may have been incomplete,
尽管下载到的铁堡数据不完整
but we now possess four sets of coordinates decoded by the ship.
但我们已经拥有了战舰所破译的四个坐标
If we are to have any hope of recovering the Iacon relics before the Decepticons do,
如果我们想赶在霸天虎之前得到铁堡的遗物
we must divide our resources.
我们就必须分头行动
But, Optimus,
但是擎天柱
when it comes to numbers, we are already at a grave disadvantage.
我们人手本来就不足…
Dispatching multiple squadrons will enable us to pursue all four coordinates simultaneously.
派出多支小队
Triangulate coordinates of the other three relics.
同时开始定位另外三组坐标
This is one race that we absolutely cannot afford to lose.
这是一场我们输不起的竞赛
The coordinates indicate that the second of these four Iacon relics
坐标显示第二个铁堡遗物位于
lies at the very bottom of this world.
这个世界的最底端
I will journey to the ends of this or any world
为了贯彻您的意志
to serve your will, lord Megatron.
我愿意前往任何世界的尽头 威震天陛下
Then return with my prize, Dreadwing.
那就带着我的战利品回来 骇翼！
and prove you are more worthy of being my second-in-command
向我证明 作为一个副官
than those who have preceded you.
你比你的前任更加称职
Inner stat, cross clamp, laser scalpel,
指数仪 十字钳 激光手术刀
durabyllium drill, and one slightly damaged but operational T-cog.
钻头 还有一个轻微损伤的变形齿轮
courtesy of my traitorous clone...
来自我那狡诈的克隆体
everything I require to make myself whole.
能够将我完全修复的设备一应俱全
A simple, painless procedure.
只是一个简单 无痛的手术
Nothing to it, really.
真的没什么
Provided one possesses the nerve.
只要有勇气
Hmm?
嗯？
Four detachments of Decepticons Ground Bridging to four different continents at the exact same time?
四支霸天虎分队同时经过环陆桥前往四个不同地点？
Ah. Procedure postponed.
啊…手术推迟！
Be on your guard, Bulkhead.
小心行事 隔板
Raphael, lock on to the remaining coordinates.
拉斐尔 锁定其余坐标
I will embark for the Antarctic.
我将前往南极
As for you, old friend,
至于你 我的老朋友
I would prefer that you have company on your mission.
我想让一个人陪同你执行任务
No one is left to join me, Optimus.
没有人能跟我同行了 擎天柱
Even if Agent Fowler were alert...
即便福勒探员恢复意识
Em? Who's talking about me?
嗯…在说我什么？
He's human.
他也不过是个人类
I was considering the only remaining Autobot alternative on this planet.
这个星球上还有一个汽车人 我想他是最终人选
But, you... you can't be serious!
等等 你不是认真的吧！
Wheeljack is insubordinate, a ruffian.
千斤顶桀骜不驯 粗俗无礼
Besides, he's Bulkhead's partner.
更何况 他是隔板的搭档
Your expertise is scientific,
你的专长是科技
but Wheeljack is a highly capable warrior.
而千斤顶是个强大的战士
You would be wise to welcome the temporary alliance.
由他暂时陪同对你有好处
Ah, a remote control for the Ground Bridge.
啊 操作环陆桥的遥控器
I love Decepticon scientists.
我爱霸天虎的科学家
I despise this planet.
呃…我讨厌这个星球！
If it isn't a scorching desert,
不是灼热的沙漠
it is a frigid wasteland.
就是寒冷的不毛之地！
Now, where are you, my Decepticon brethren?
好了 我的霸天虎兄弟们你们在哪儿？
Faster, you pathetic excuse for transportation!
啊！快跑啊 你这悲催的蠢玩意儿！
Decepticons, do you not realize you have just shot down your ship's Commander?!
霸天虎！知道你们打下了自己的战舰指挥官吗？
Aah!
啊！
You command no one, deserter.
你指挥不了任何人 叛徒！
Skyquake? B-but you're...
天震？但是 你已经…！
You mistake me for my brother,
你把我和我兄弟搞混了
who is one with the Allspark,
他已经与火种源同在了
as you are, no doubt, aware, former commander Starscream.
你最清楚他怎么死的 前任指挥官 红蜘蛛…
Ahhh... Hahaha...
啊…哈…哈哈哈
Were it up to me,
要是我能做得了主
I would end this here and now.
我立马就会在这里把你了结
But it is my duty as first lieutenant to Megatron
但是作为威震天陛下的副官
to render all traitors to my lord and master
将叛徒带给我的主人进行公正的审判
for due punishment.
是我的职责
First lieutenant?!
副官？
That's my post!
那是我的官位！
Uh, was my post.
呃 曾经 是我的
Commander Dreadwing,
骇翼指挥官
this must be a very important mission if Megatron has dispatched his second-in-command.
威震天会派他的副手来 一定是一项十分重要的任务
Scouting for Energon, or something else altogether?
是搜寻能量 还是其他的什么事？
That is none of your concern.
与你无关
If I knew what you were looking for,
要是告诉我你在找什么
perhaps I could help.
或许我能提供帮助
We have arrived at the coordinates.
我们已经到达了坐标地点
The relic. It has been taken.
遗物 已经被带走了！
Relic? What sort of relic?
遗物？什么遗物？
Search the area!
搜索附近区域！
Commander Dreadwing,
骇翼指挥官
we have discovered vehicle tracks.
发现车辆的痕迹
The Autobots.
汽车人！
Perhaps. Though I've never known them to plant flags
虽然有可能 但我从来不知道
at the site of their victories.
他们还会留下旗帜夸示胜利
Do not try me, traitor.
别挑战我的耐性 叛徒！
I will leave your lifeless husk in this frozen waste.
我会把你抛尸在这片冻原上
You two, guard the prisoner.
你们两个 看着囚犯
Optimus Prime, I will request only once that you surrender the relic.
擎天柱 我只说一次 交出遗物！
I was going to request the same of you, Dreadwing.
我把这话还给你 骇翼
Then I would say that we are on equal footing,
那看来我们在同一起跑线上
were it not that there are five of us and only one of you.
只不过 我们是五对一
Six, if you'd relieve me of these ridiculous manacles.
是六 要是你给我解开这荒唐的手铐
Your aim is poor.
你的准头真差
That is a matter of perspective.
只是目标不同罢了！
No!
不！
A stalemate would leave us where?
这样僵持下去我们能…怎么样？
Commander Dreadwing!
骇翼指挥官！
What a team we make!
我们配合真默契！
I am so glad that you prevailed, Optimus Prime!
我很高兴你能获胜 擎天柱！
That wretch Dreadwing was going to terminate me.
那个可恶的骇翼差点杀了我！
Now, if you could just remove my bonds,
好了 只要你给我解开手铐
I can lead you straight to the relic.
我就带你去遗物那里
You will lead me there regardless.
不解开你也得带我去
Hmph. You're welcome.
哼 不客气…
Be reasonable, Prime!
讲点道理 擎天柱！
This cold will freeze both our actuators.
严寒会把我们的促动器都冻住的！
The current temperatures are not extreme enough to affect our biology.
这里的温度很低 但不足以影响到我们的生理构造
You'll be fine.
你不会有事的
Fine but miserable.
没事 却不好过！
And I cannot believe that you take our alliances for granted.
真没想到 我为汽车人做了那么多
After all I have done for the Autobots...
你却毫不领情！
helping to restore your memory,
帮助你恢复记忆
saving Arcee's life.
救了阿尔茜一命
While you have at times proved beneficial to us,
你偶尔向我们提供帮助
it has been only to further your own interests.
只不过是为了你自己的利益
Well, we can't all be as selfless as you, now, can we?
好吧 但我们不可能都像你那样无私 不是吗？
Aha, as I suspected...
啊哈！如我所料
humans. We will find the relic here.
人类…遗物肯定在这里
So, let us reclaim what is rightfully ours. Aah!
让我们夺回本属于我们的东西吧 啊！
We cannot simply enter a human facility to search for Cybertronian relics.
我们不能就这样冲进一个人类设施 去搜索塞博特恩的圣物
Not even if they stole it?
哪怕是他们偷走的 也不行？
Nor can I expose innocent humans to a dangerous Decepticon.
我也不能让无辜的人类面对一个危险的霸天虎！
Rafael, has Agent Fowler regained consciousness?
拉斐尔 福勒探员恢复知觉了吗？
I'm here, Prime. What's your situation?
我在这儿 擎天柱 你那边是什么情况？
I require access to a research facility at my current coordinates.
我需要进入一处考察站 就在我所在的位置
Let me make a call.
让我联系一下
Are we really going to wait out here in the freezing cold,
我们就这么干等着挨冻？
completely at the mercy of human bureaucracy?!
完全被人类官僚驱使？
Base is clear, Prime. Try not to wreck the joint.
基地已经清空了 擎天柱 尽量不要破坏设施
Many thanks, Agent Fowler.
十分感谢 福勒探员
The relic remained sealed in the ice.
遗物仍被封在冰中
I knew you were of questionable honor, Starscream,
虽然早知道你毫无羞耻之心 红蜘蛛
but aiding the Autobots,
但你竟然投靠汽车人
that is a capital offense.
这是我容忍的极限了
What?!
什么？
But I... I left tracks for you on purpose!
但是我 我特意给你留下了记号！
so you could rescue me from my captor.
好让你来营救我！
Dreadwing, I cannot allow you to leave here with this relic.
骇翼 我不会让你带走遗物的
I know that, Prime,
我知道 擎天柱
but I do not intend to give you a choice.
但我不打算给你选择的余地！
Given all the fuss, this relic must be truly special.
如此兴师动众 这遗物必定非同凡响！
Armor... of Decepticon origin.
一件护甲 出自霸天虎之手
The Apex armor.
精锐护甲…
A perfect fit.
十分合身！
You dare to claim that which rightfully belongs to Lord Megatron?
你竟敢染指本属于威震天陛下的东西？
And what do you intend to do about it, Commander?
你能奈我何 指挥官？
Not so big and strong now, are you?
现在你看起来没那么高大强壮了 不是吗？
I haven't had this much fun since I punched that hole in Cliffjumper.
自从上次在飞过山身上打个洞以来 我还从没这么高兴过！
Allow me to reunite you with your beloved twin.
让我送你去见你心爱的双胞胎兄弟吧
And you, Optimus Prime.
而你 擎天柱
I will beat the living Spark out of you,
我要把你的火种活生生地敲出来
just so I never again have to endure your pontificating.
这样我就不用再忍受你那装模作样的态度了！
Dreadwing, our battle remains unfinished,
骇翼 我们的战斗还未结束
but if we do not unite against our common foe...
但如果我们不团结起来对付我们共同的敌人…
Starscream will destroy us both.
红蜘蛛会把我们都干掉
I will draw his attention.
我去吸引他注意力
Might beats flight.
力气大不怕你会飞！
You shall be the one to join with the Allspark.
你才该魂归火种源！
That tickled! Ahhhahaha... Fools!
像挠痒痒一样 哈哈哈 蠢货们！
Not only am I intelligent, I am invincible!
本座现在不光是英明 而且神武！
Yet you cannot fly.
但是你不能飞！
Nobody's perfect.
没有人是完美的
Now, tell me of the other three relics.
好了 告诉我另外三个遗物
Are they as powerful as my shiny new armor?
是不是也像我这件闪亮的新装甲一样威力无穷？
They were hidden away precisely to keep them from the hands of those like you.
正是为了避免像你这样的人染指
He is far too powerful, Prime! Fall back!
他的威力太强大了 擎天柱！后退！
Cowards.
懦夫
You will not escape my might.
你们休想逃出我的掌心！
Wait.
等等
You two are up to something.
你们想算计我？
Now that our alliance has served its purpose...
现在 我们联手的目的已经达到了
Starscream is gone and the Apex armor with him.
精锐护甲随着红蜘蛛一起消失了
Is there really a need to renew battle when the goal has been lost?
没有了目标 还有必要继续打下去吗？
We have other unfinished matters.
我们还有别的账要算…
I bore Skyquake no malice,
我对天震没有恶意
and I regret the role I played in his demise,
我导致了他的死亡 我也很遗憾
so I will appeal to you as I once did your twin...
所以我也向你提出相同的请求
turn your back on the Decepticon cause
离开霸天虎势力
and help me end this war.
协助我结束这场战争
For his sake, and for all who have fallen.
为了你兄弟和所有牺牲的战士
You saved my life today.
今天你救了我一命
I will terminate you the next time we meet.
下次见面我再杀你！
So be it, Dreadwing.
如此也罢 骇翼